Finding Aid for Jerome W. Conn papers, 1931-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Jerome W. Conn papers 1931-1994, 1954-1975
Conn, Jerome W., 1907-1994.
4 linear feet
9617 Aa 2
Professor internal medicine and director of the Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism at the University of Michigan. Conn was discoverer of Primary Aldosteronism (Conn's Syndrome) and its cure through the surgical removal of the adrenal tumor. The collection has been divided into three series: personal, professional, and topical files. The collection includes correspondence, research files and notes, subject files, published materials, and photographs relating to his research and other professional activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Phyllis Conn Muller (Donor no. 8409 ) in 1995.
The collection is open to research.
Jerome Conn was born in New York City on September 24, 1907. He graduated from Rutgers University in 1932 and then received his medical degree from the University of Michigan in 1935. Conn joined the faculty of the University of Michigan an instructor of internal medicine immediately upon graduation. He remained at the university until his retirement in 1973 being promoted to full professor in 1950 and also serving as director of the Division of Endocrinology from 1943 to 1973. From 1973 to 1976, Conn was Veterans Administration Distinguished Physician at which time he retired to Naples, Florida where he died in 1994.
Conn was a world-renowned medical pioneer whose laboratory research uncovered a disease caused by an adrenal tumor, now known as Primary Aldosteronism or Conn's Syndrome. Through his research, Conn demonstrated that the disease, caused by an adrenal tumor secreting excessive amounts of the adrenal hormone aldosterone, was a major cause of hypertension and that through the surgical removal of the adrenal tumor, Primary Aldosteronism could be controlled. Because of his research in this and other areas, Conn was a frequent lecturer at professional conferences and author of hundreds of articles.
The Conn collection, covering the years of 1931 to 1994, has been divided into three series: Personal, Professional, and Topical Files.
Subjects:
Conn, Jerome W., 1907-1994.; Aldosterone.; Hypertension.; University of Michigan. Division of Endocrinology and Metabolism.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Medical School.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Conn, Jerome W., 1907-1994.; Laboratories--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Teachers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Laboratories.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Teachers.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Personal
  The Personal series consists of biographical information, photographs, and accumulated files pertaining to the many awards and honors received throughout his career.
  - Biographical Articles 1938-1994 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Sketches (Box 1)
  - Honors and Awards
    - Press
      - 1931-1961 (Box 1)
      - 1962-1968 (Box 1)
      - 1963-1969 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1969 (Box 1)
    - Certificates 1964-1986 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, 1957-1969 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan class of 1932, 1938-1972 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1932-1992 (Box 1)
- Professional
  The Professional series includes lectures given by Dr. Conn, also newspaper and journal articles relating to his work. This series also includes Dr. Conn's clinical research files and notes. As much of the material in this series is undated, it has been grouped by subject. The largest category of material relates to Primary Aldosteronism (Conn's Syndrome).
  - Certificates and Licenses (Box 1)
  - Clinical Research
    - Aldersterone
      - 1956-1972 (Box 1)
      - 1973-1978 (Box 1)
    - Diabetes 1964 (Box 1)
    - Dog Experiments
      - 1966 (Box 1)
      - 1967 (Box 1)
    - Hypertension 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Box 1)
    - Primary Aldosteronism, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Primary Reinism (Box 2)
    - Urinary Aldosteronism (Box 2)
  - Clinical Research Notes
    - Alderstone (Box 2)
    - Diabetes (Box 2)
    - Hypertension (Box 2)
    - Primary Aldosteronism, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Jerome W. Conn Symposium
    - 1974 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1974 (Box 2)
  - Lectures and papers
    - Aldersterone (Box 2)
    - Diabetes
      - A-K (Box 2)
      - L-Z (Box 2)
    - Hypertension (Box 2)
    - Hypoglycemia (Box 2)
    - Primary Aldosteronism
      - A-D (Box 2)
      - E-Pre (Box 2)
      - Pri (Box 3)
      - R-S (Box 3)
  - Lecture Programs
    - 1937-1948 (Box 3)
    - 1949-1951 (Box 3)
    - 1952-1958 (Box 3)
    - 1959-1966 (Box 3)
    - 1967-1973 (Box 3)
    - 1974-1978 (Box 3)
  - Lecture Slides and Photographs, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Press
    - Aldersterone
      - 1955-1967 (Box 3)
      - 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    - Diabetes
      - 1948-1959 (Box 4)
      - 1960-1972 (Box 4)
    - Hypertension 1962-1969 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Topics 1935-1959 (Box 4)
    - Primary Aldosteronism
      - 1952-1964 (Box 4)
      - 1965-1972 (Box 4)
  - Published Work
    - Lists 1936-1977 (Box 4)
    - Diabetes 1949-1963 (Box 4)
    - Hypertension Oversize 1965 (Box 4)
    - Hypoglycemia 1970 (Box 4)
    - Primary Aldosteronism 1956-1976 (Box 4)
  - Reviews
    - 1973-1975 (Box 4)
    - 1976-1980 (Box 4)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series consists largely of administrative material or correspondence dealing with various medical organizations with which Dr. Conn was involved or about which he was concerned.
  - Aldersterone Conferences 1971-1976 (Box 4)
  - Aldersterone Workshop
    - 1971 (Box 4)
    - 1972 (Box 4)
  - American College of Physicians 1978 (Box 4)
  - American Diabetes Association 1958-1976 (Box 4)
  - American Medical Association 1974 (Box 4)
  - Council for High Blood Pressure (Box 4)
  - Hypoglycemia Foundation 1965-1974 (Box 4)
  - International Society for Cardiology 1967-1978 (Box 4)
  - International Study Group for Steroid Hormones 1973 (Box 4)
  - Medcom Faculty of Medicine 1971-1975 (Box 4)
  - Naples Community Hospital 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Senior Medical Consultants 1978 (Box 4)
  - State of Michigan,1961-1977 (Box 4)
  - Veterans' Administration
    - 1971-1974 (Box 4)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan
    - Administrative Correspondence 1969-1973 (Box 4)
    - Policies 1973 (Box 4)
    - Salary 1944-1961 (Box 4)
    - Photographs 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - World Health Organization 1966-1973 (Box 4)